<font color=#00FFFF>-=TLF Movie TEAM=-
<font color=#00FFFF>-=星际迷航 TLF字幕组校对:剑风 压制:DKa1688=-
<font color=#00FFFF>仅供交流  严禁商用</font>
-星舰开尔文号呼叫星舰基地  -星舰基地收到
- USS Kelvin, go for Starfleet base. - Starfleet Base.
我们已经发送数据  请确认是否收到
We sent you a transmission. Did you receive it?
开尔文号  请复核这些数据
Kelvin, can you double-check those readings?
我们的重力感应器失灵  非常奇怪
Our gravitational sensors are going crazy here. You should see this.
看起来像电磁风暴
It looks like a lightning storm.
你发送的数据看起来似乎不可能
What you've sent us doesn't seem possible.
是的  长官  我了解  所以我们才发送它
Yes mam, I understand. That's why we sent it.
-报告情况  -还有20秒进入目视距离
- Report. - Still outta visual range. 20 seconds.
报告瑞博舰长  星际舰队建议采取防御行动
Alert captain Robau that Starfleet advised to proceed with caution...
分屏显示
Polarize the view screen.
-这是什么...克林贡人吗  -舰长  已经显示
- Whatever this is... Klingon origin? - Captain, we have visual.
-重复  会是克林贡吗  -不是  上尉
- Repeat. Could this be Klingon? - Negative, lieutenant.
你们距离克林贡边境75000英里以外
You're 75000 kilometers from the Klingon border.
舰长  你看...
Captain, are you seeing this?
天啊
My God.
收到报告  对方武器已经锁定我们
I have a reading. They've locked weapons on us!
红色警戒
Red alert!
-我们已被鱼雷锁定  方向320度  二号位  -准备武器
- Torpedo locked on us at 320'- 2! - Arm weapons!
执行D-5回避方式
Evasive pattern delta 5!
我们正遭受严重攻击
We're being cut like grass.
发射所有激光炮  报告损害情况
Fire all phasers! Damage report.
曲速引擎损坏  从没见过这种情况
Warp drive's been knocked out. Never seen anything like this.
武器系统中断  主动力剩余38％
Weapons offline. Main power at 38%.
-他们正发射另一颗  -所有能量集中到前护盾
- They're firing another! - All power to forward shields!
救救我...
Help me...
失去机动力
Maneuver has been lost.
护盾是否启用
Are shields even on?
已经确认17层和13层甲板的伤亡者
Decks 17 and 13, we have confirmed casualties.
护盾剩余11%  还在下降  10%  9%
11% and dropping. 10%. Shields at 9%.
所有剩余能量转移到前护盾
All remaining power to forward shields.
准备撤离用飞船
Prepare shuttles for evacuation.
你们好
Hello.
我的司令官要求见你们的舰长
My commander requests the presence of your captain...
以谈判停火条件
In order to negotiate a ceasefire.
你必须乘坐飞船到我们舰上来
You will come aboard our ship via shuttlecraft.
你若拒绝  那就太蠢了
Your refusal would be unwise.
跟我来
Walk with me.
如果15分钟内我没有消息  全舰撤离
If I don't report in 15 minutes evacuate the crew.
-长官，我们可以...  -在这里我们孤立无援
- Sir, we could... - There is no outpost out here.
使用自动飞行  然后弃船
Use autopilot and get off this ship.
明白  舰长
Aye captain.
你现在是舰长了  柯克先生
You're captain now, Mr. Kirk.
他的心跳加快了
His heart rate is elevated.
看这艘船
Look at the ship.
-你熟悉这艘船吗  -你的司令官是谁
- Are you familiar with this craft? - Who is your commander?
-那就是他吗  -我代表尼禄舰长发言
- Is that him? - I will speak for captain Nero.
那么请问尼罗舰长
Then ask captain Nero:
谁给他权力肆意攻击联邦星舰的
What gives him the right to attack a Federation vessel.
你知道斯波克大使在那里吗
Do you know the location of ambassador Spock?
我不知道什么斯波克大使
I'm unfamiliar with ambassador Spock.
-现在是星历哪年  -哪一年
- What is the current star date? - Star date?
2233.04
2233.04.
你们来自哪里
Where are you from?
已死亡
Terminated.
长官  他们已经锁定我们的信号
Sir, they have a lock on our signal.
他们准备再次开火
They're launching again.
B-6方案 全方位开火
Bravo 6 maneuver fire, full spread!
我下达13号舰长令  全员撤离
I'm initiating general order 13, we're evacuating!
是  长官
Sir.
所有舰层注意  我是舰长  立即弃船逃生
All decks, this is the captain speaking, evacuate the ship immediately.
迅速前往指定飞船  开始撤离
Get your... to the shuttlecraft. Begin evacuating...
是乔治的声音  发生什么了
That's George's voice. What's happening?
我们得去逃生艇分娩  快
We'll deliver it in the shuttle. Go!
-乔治  -你很好  感谢上帝
- George. - You're OK, thank God.
37号医疗逃生艇待命中  你现在过去  可以吗
I have medical shuttle 37 standing by. Get to it now. Can you do that?
可以
Yes.
一切都会好的
Everything's gonna be OK.
照我说的做  去37号逃生艇
Do exactly as I say, shuttle 37.
乔治  快了
George, it's coming.
-我们的孩子快出生了  -我马上到
- Our baby. It's coming now. - I'm on my way.
自动驾驶系统失效  只能人工控制
Autopilot function has been destroyed. Manual operation only.
清理甲板  赶往逃生艇  快  快  快
Clear those decks now! Get to the shuttles! Move! Move! Move!
-越来越厉害了  -继续呼吸  你会好的
- That was a big one! - Just keep breathing. You'll be fine.
-宝宝也一样 对吧  -宝宝也会没事的
- And the baby too, right? - And the baby too.
就在这里
Right here.
舰长呼叫37号逃生艇  我的妻子在吗
Captain to shuttle 37. Is my wife on board?
-是的长官  她在  -我要你们立刻出发  明白吗
- Yes sir, she is. - I need you to go now. Do you hear me?
-我们会等您的  长官  -不  你们立即离开
- We're waiting on you sir. - No, just go, take off immediately.
-这是命令  -明白  长官
- That's an order. - Yes sir.
等等  我们还不能出发
Wait. We're not going yet.
求你停下
Please stop.
乔治  逃生艇要离开了  你在哪里
George, the shuttle's leaving. Where are you?
亲爱的  听我说  我不能赶过去了
Sweetheart, listen to me. I'm not gonna be there.
-不  -这是让你活下去的唯一方法
- No. - This is the only way you'll survive.
别留在船上  到我身边来
Please don't stay on the ship. Come to me here.
如果我不打败他们  飞船是逃不掉的
The shuttles will never make it if I don't fight them off.
乔治  我不能没有你
George, I can't do this without you.
好的  现在用力
OK, I need you to push now!
系统失效
SYSTEMS FAILING
碰撞进程启动
COLLISION COURSE ENGAGED
-怎么样  -是个男孩
- What is it? - It's a boy.
男孩
A boy?
-跟我说说他  -他很美
- Tell me about him. - He's beautiful.
乔治  你应该在这里的
George, you should be here.
撞击警告
Impact alert.
我们给他起什么名字
What are we gonna call him?
我们可以起你父亲的名字
We can name him after your father.
泰比里厄斯  你开玩笑吧  不  那太糟了
Tiberius, you kiddin' me? No, that's the worst.
起你父亲的名字吧  叫他詹姆斯
Let's name him after your dad. Let's call him Jim.
詹姆斯  好  就叫詹姆斯
Jim. OK. Jim it is.
-亲爱的  你能听到我吗  -能
- Sweetheart can you hear me? - I can hear...
我太爱你了
I love you so much.
我爱你
I love you!
星际迷航
爱荷华州
你疯了吗  那车子可是古董
Hey, are you out of your mind? That car is an antique.
你以为你妈不在地球上你就不会被罚了吗
You think you can get away with this just because your mother's off planet.
现在马上滚回家  你住的可是我的房子
You get your ass back home now! You live in my house buddy.
你住我的房子  开我的车
You live in my house and that's my car.
你弄伤一道划痕  我就让你尝尝竹笋肉片...
You get one scratch on that car and I'm gonna whip your ass...
约翰尼
Hey Johnny!
先生  请靠边停车
Citizen, pull over.
不
Noooo...!
有问题吗  警察先生
Is there a problem officer?
先生  你叫什么名字
Citizen, what is your name?
我叫詹姆斯·泰比里厄斯·柯克
My name is James Tiberius Kirk.
瓦肯星
球的体积公式是什么
What is the formula for the volume of a sphere?
4/3×π×(R^3)...
4/3 PI times the radius cubed...
1.26...
维度是多少...
What is the dimensionality...
维度等于n的对数处以...
Dimensionality equals the logarithm of n divided by...
无排他性及无敌对性...
non-excludability and non-rivalry...
4/3×π×(R^3)...
...4/3 PI times the radius...
精神上值得称颂  但实际无此义务
...is morally praiseworthy but not morally obligatory.
斯波克
Spock.
我想你已经准备好今天新的侮辱了吧
I presume you've prepared new insults for today?
不错
Affirmative.
这是你第35次试图引起我的情绪反映
This is your 35th attempt to illicit an emotional response from me.
你既非人也非瓦肯人  在宇宙没有立足之地
You're neither Human nor Vulcan and therefore have no place in this universe.
看  他的人眼  那是哀伤  不是吗
Look, his Human eyes. They look sad. Don't they.
或许需要一些肉体上的刺激才能让你生气
Perhaps an emotional response requires physical stimulate.
你的父亲是个叛徒
He's a traitor you know? Your father.
他娶了那个人类娼妓
For marrying her. That Human whore.
他们说您是叛徒
They called you a traitor.
我们的种族情感深沉
Emotions run deep within our race.
许多方面来说  远比人类更为深邃
In many ways more deeply than in humans.
逻辑能提供给镇定者难得的体验
Logic offers a serenity humans seldom experience.
控制住情感  你才不会受它们控制
The control of feelings... So that they do not control you.
您建议我应该彻底成为瓦肯人
You suggest that I should be completely Vulcan?
但你却娶了一个人类女性
And yet you married a Human.
作为地球大使  我的职责就是观察
As ambassador to Earth it is my duty to observe
并理解人类的行为
And understand Human behavior.
娶了你的母亲...很符合逻辑
Marrying your mother was... logical.
斯波克
Spock.
你完全能够决定自己的命运
You are fully capable of deciding your own destiny.
问题是  你会选择哪条路
The question you face is:Which path will you choose?
有些事只有你自己才能决定
This is something only you can decide.
斯波克  过来  让妈看看你
Spock. Come here, let me see you.
-不  -斯波克
- No. - Spock.
不用担心  你会好的
There's no need to be anxious. You'll do fine.
我不担心  妈妈
I am hardly anxious, mother.
"好"的定义太多了  "好"无法令人接受
And fine has variable definitions, fine is unacceptable.
好吧
Okay.
-我能问个私人问题吗  -当然可以
- May I ask a personal query? - Anything.
我应该完成瓦肯的柯里纳训练
Should I choose to complete the Vulcan discipline of Kolinahr.
去除所有情感吗
And purge all emotion?
我相信您不会以为 这是针对你的
I trust you will not feel it reflects judgment upon you.
斯波克
Oh Spock.
一如以往  无论你选择什么  妈妈以你为荣
As always, whatever you choose to be, you will have a proud mother.
你的成绩远胜导师的预期
You have surpassed the expectations of your instructors.
你的记录完美无瑕  除了一点
Your final record is flawless. With one exception.
我注意到你也申请了联邦星舰
I see that you have applied to Starfleet as well.
为自己准备多项选择 完全符合逻辑
It was logical to cultivate more options.
合乎逻辑  但不必要
Logical, but unnecessary.
兹宣布  你已被瓦肯科学研究院接受
You are hereby accepted to the Vulcan Science Academy.
斯波克  你很优秀  虽有劣势
It is truly remarkable Spock that you have achieved so much...
却能获得如此多的成就
despite your disadvantage.
起立
All rise.
议长先生  你能说明你指的什么短处吗
If you would clarify, minister? To what disadvantage are you referring?
你的人类母亲
Your Human mother.
议会  议长们  我必须谢绝
Council, ministers, I must decline.
从来没有瓦肯人曾经拒绝进入这所学院
No Vulcan has ever declined admission to this Academy.
既然我是半人类  您的记录将依旧无瑕
But as I am half-human, your record remains untarnished.
斯波克  你承诺过会遵循瓦肯方式的
Spock, you have made a commitment to honor the Vulcan way.
你今日为何还要走到议会面前
Why did you come before this council today?
为了让你的叛逆情绪得到满足吗
Was it to satisfy your emotional need to rebel?
我唯一想表达的情感就是感谢
The only emotion I wish to convey is gratitude.
谢谢议会和议长们对我的关心
Thank you, ministers, for your consideration.
生生不息  繁荣昌盛
Live long and prosper.
-你好  -好
- Hi. - Hey there.
你好  我要一杯星鳗火茶  三杯经典百威
Hi. I'd like a Clabmin fire tea... 3 Budweiser Classics,
两杯卡达西恩日落和...
2 Cardassian sunrises and...
-试试莎休酒  不错的  -一杯莎休调酒  谢谢
- Try the Slusho, it's good. - A Slusho mix, thank you.
作为女人  喝得可真够多的
That's a lot of drinks for a woman.
-还有一杯不加冰的杰克  -双份  算在我账上
- And a shot of Jack, straight up. - Make that two. Her shot's on me.
我自己付钱  谢谢  不用你付
Her shot's on her. Thanks, but no thanks.
你彻底拒绝我之前就不想知道我的名字吗
Don't you at least wanna know my name before you completely reject me?
我不问也无所谓
I'm fine without it.
你不问也无所谓  我叫詹姆斯·柯克
You are fine without it. It's Jim, Jim Kirk.
你要是不告诉我名字  我只好自己编一个
If you don't tell me your name, I'm gonna have to make one up.
-我叫乌胡拉  -乌胡拉  不会吧
- It's Uhura. - Uhura? No way.
我正想替你起这个名
That's the name I was gonna make up for you.
-乌胡拉  姓呢  -没有姓
- Uhura what? - Just Uhura.
你们的世界是没有姓的吗
They don't have last names in your world?
乌胡拉就是我的姓
Uhura is my last name.
那你们的世界是没有名的吗
Well they don't have last names in your world?
借过  老兄
Excuse me buddy.
你是学员  学什么的
So, you're a cadet, your studying. What's your focus?
外星语言学  你根本不知道这词的意思吧
Xenolinguistics. You have no idea what that means.
外星人语言的研究  形态学 音韵学 句法
The study of alien languages. Morphology, phonology, syntax.
看来你很有语言天赋
Means you've got a talented tongue.
我很惊讶
I'm impressed.
刚才  我还以为你只是个呆头呆脑的乡巴佬
For a moment there, I thought you were just a dumb-hair colonial
只会找牲口发泄
Who has sex with farm animals.
可不只是牲口
Well, not only.
这个土老帽没骚扰你吧
This townie isn't bothering you, right?
骚扰得厉害  不过我应付得来
Oh, beyond belief. But it's nothing I can't handle.
你能应付  这算是邀请吗
You could've handled me. That's an invitation.
-喂  你最好识相点  -别紧张  亲爱的  玩笑而已
- Hey. You better mind your manners. - Oh relax cupcake, it was a joke.
乡巴佬  你会数数吗
Hey farm boy, maybe you can't count.
我们有四个人对付你一个
There are 4 of us and 1 of you.
再多找点人吧  那样才公平
So get some more guys and then it'll be an even fight.
伙计们  住手
Guys. Stop it.
住手
Stop it!
够了
Enough!
伙计们  够了
Guys, he's had enough.
全部出去
Outside. All of you.
-现在  -是的  长官
- Now. - Yes, sir.
-什么...  -我只是喝杯酒
- What... - I just bought a drink.
你还好吗  孩子
You all right, son?
你口哨吹得真好
You can whistle really loud, you know that?
酒保告诉我你是谁的时候我简直不敢相信
You know I couldn't believe it when the bartender told me who you are.
-我是谁  派克船长  -你父亲的儿子
- Who the hell am I, captain Pike? - Your father's son.
能再给我一杯吗
Can I get another one?
我写过关于联邦星舰开尔文号的学术论文
For my dissertation I was assigned USS Kelvin.
我欣赏你父亲  他不相信有不可能赢的时候
Something I admired about your dad, he didn't believe in no-win scenarios.
他肯定是经验丰富
Sure learned his lesson.
那取决于你如何定义"胜利"
Well that depends on how you define winning.
-你在听我说吧  -谢谢
- You're here, aren't you? - Thanks.
不加思考直接行动  也是他的天性之一
You know that instinct to leap without looking, that was his nature too...
我认为这正是联邦舰队所失去的
And in my opinion something Starfleet's lost.
你为什么和我说这些
Why are you talking to me man?
因为我在你泡妞的时候看了你的档案
Because I looked up your file while you were drooling on the floor.
你的能力倾向测验出类拔萃  那问题是什么
Your aptitude tests are off the charts, so what is it?
你想喜欢成为中西部唯一一名天才惯犯吗
You like being the only genius level repeat-offender in the mid-west?
或许我爱得很呢
Maybe I love it.
那么是父亲的死让你满足于平淡的生活
So your dad dies, you can saddle for less than an ordinary life.
还是  你认为自己应得更好的  更为特别的
Or do you feel that you were meant for something better? Something special?
-加入星际舰队吧  -入伍
- Enlist in Starfleet. - Enlist?
你们这个月的招募额肯定是低过头了吧
You guys must be way down on your recruiting quarter for the month.
如果你有你父亲一半能力  詹姆斯
If you're half the man your father was Jim,
星际舰队就能用得上你
Starfleet could use you.
你可以在四年内成为军官  八年内当上舰长
You can be an officer in 4 years, you can have your own ship in 8.
你明白星际联邦是什么  对吧  这很重要
You understand what the Federation is, don't you? It's important,
它是一支维护和平及人道主义的舰队
It's a peacekeeping and humanitarian armada.
说完了吗
We done?
我说完了
I'm done.
河边船坞  新人招募艇明早八点离开
Riverside shipyard. Shuttle for new recruits leaves tomorrow - 08:00.
你的父亲当了12分钟舰长
Your father was captain of a starship for 12 minutes.
他救了800条命  包括你们母子俩的
He saved 800 lives, including your mother's and yours.
我谅你也做不到更好了
I dare you to do better.
车够帅啊  哥们
Nice ride man.
送给你了
It's yours.
四年吗  我会在三年内做到
4 years? I'll do it in 3.
放松点  先生们
At ease gentlemen.
一直没打听到名字
Never did get that first name.
-你需要医生  -我跟你们说了
- You need a doctor. - I told you people,
我不需要医生  该死  我就是医生
I don't need a doctor, damn it. I am a doctor.
你得回到自己座位上
You need to get back to your seat.
我的就在没窗户的盥洗室里
I had one, in the bathroom with no windows.
我有惧飞症  我对能上天的东西都怕得要死
I suffer from aviofobia. That means fear of dying in something that flies.
先生  为了安全请您坐下  否则我得强迫您
Sir, for your own safety, sit down or else I'll make you sit down!
-好吧  -谢谢合作
- Fine. - Thank you.
我是派克舰长  我们准备起飞
This is captain Pike, we've been cleared for takeoff.
我可能会吐在你身上
I may throw up on you.
-我想这里很安全  -别安慰我了孩子
- I think these things are pretty safe. - Don't pander with me kid.
船上有一条小缝  我们的血液将在13秒内沸腾
One tiny crack in the hull and our blood boils in 13 seconds.
突发一次太阳耀斑  我们将被烤熟在椅子上
A solar flare might crop up, cook us in our seats.
等着看你走运地患上安多里安疱疹吧
And while you're sitting pretty with a case of Andorian shingles,
看你双眼流血的时候  还能不能这么镇定
See if you're still so relaxed when your eyeballs are bleeding.
太空就是被黑暗和沉寂掩盖的疾病和危险
Space is disease and danger, wrapped in darkness and silence.
我不想跟你说破  但星舰就是在太空航行的
Well I hate to break this to you, but Starfleet operates in space.
对  我没别的地儿可去了
Yeah, well... I've got nowhere else to go,
离婚时  前妻抢走了整颗星球
The ex wife took the whole damn planet in the divorce.
我就剩下这把老骨头
All I've got left is my bones.
-詹姆斯·柯克  -麦科伊  伦纳德·麦科伊
- Jim Kirk. - McCoy. Leonard McCoy.
三年后
Three years later.
尼禄舰长  舰桥请您过去  长官
Captain Nero. You've been requested on the bridge, sir.
阿伊尔说时候到了
Ayel says it's time.
长官  我们已经抵达您所计算的坐标
Sir, we've arrived at the coordinates we calculated.
但这里空无一物  您的命令是
There's nothing here. What are your orders?
我们等
We wait.
等那个听任我们家园被毁的人到来
We wait for the one who allowed our home to be destroyed.
正如我们这25年来所做的
As we've been doing for 25 years.
-等我们杀了他之后呢  -杀了他
- And once we've killed him? - Kill him?
我不会杀了他  我要他看着
I'm not gonna kill him. I gonna make him watch.
逮住那只船
Capture that ship.
欢迎回来  斯波克
Welcome back, Spock.
-你在高兴什么  -不知道你在说啥
- Why are you so happy? - I do not know what you're talking about.
-对  我猜你也不知道  -好啊  姑娘们
- No, I don't suppose you do. - Hello ladies.
-我要再做一次测试  -你开玩笑吧
- I'm taking the test again. - You've got to be kidding.
不开玩笑  明天上午  我要你也来
Yeah, tomorrow morning. And I want you there.
我还有比眼睁睁看你
You know I've got better things to do...
第三次给自己难堪更有价值的事情可做
Than watch you embarrass yourself for the 3rd time.
我是医生  詹姆斯  我忙得很
I am a doctor, Jim. I'm busy.
老骨头  从来没人过那个测试  你没有疑问吗
Bones, it doesn't bother you that no one's ever passed the test.
詹姆斯  那可是小林丸号测试  从来没人能过
Jim, it's Kobayashi Maru. No one passes the test.
也没人去考第二次  更别提第三次了
And no one goes back for seconds, let alone thirds.
我还得学习
I've gotta study.
你学个屁
Study, my ass.
詹姆斯  我想我爱你
Jim, I think I love you.
-好诡异  -开灯
- That is so weird. - Lights.
-你刚刚是不是说"好诡异"  -对  我说了  但...
- Did you just say that is so weird. - Yeah, I did, but I...
你不爱我吗
You don't love me too?
天  我的室友
Oh, no, my roommate.
可我记得你说过  她整晚都不会回来的
I thought you said she was gone for the night.
显然不是了  快点  到床底下去
Obviously she's not, quick, you gotta... just get under the bed.
-床底...  -就到床底去
- Under...? - Look, just get under the bed.
-不能让她看到你在这  -为啥
- She can't see you here. - Why not?
因为我向她保证过  不会再把男人带回来
Because I promised her I'd stop bringing guys back to the dorm.
-那  你到底带了多少男人...  -快下去  快
- Well how... how many guys have y...? - Just d... just down.
你怎么样
Hey. How are you?
-很好啊  -最最奇怪的事情
- Good. - Strangest thing...
我在远程传感实验室里
I was in the long range sensor lab.
我以为你会呆一整夜
Yeah, I... I thought all night...
我正追踪太阳系  突然收到紧急求救信号
I was tracking solar systems and I picked up an emergency transmission.
-真的  -对啊
- Really? - Yeah.
从一颗克林贡囚星上发出的
From a Klingon prison planet.
-不是吧  -没错
- No. - Yeah.
一支克林贡舰队被毁  47艘舰船
A Klingon armada was destroyed, 47 ships.
那你今晚就不回实验室吗
So, you're not going back to the lab tonight?
-盖尔  他是谁  -谁是谁啊
- Gaila, who is he? - Who's who?
藏你床底下  张着大嘴呼吸的那个
The mouth-breather hiding under your bed.
-你能听到我在呼吸  -你
- You could hear me breathing? - You.
-明天可是大日子  -你肯定会挂的
- Big day tomorrow. - You're gonna fail.
-盖尔  回见  -快滚
- Gail, see you around. - Get out.
要是我过了  能告诉我你的名字吗
If I pass will you tell me your first name?
不行  晚安
No. Good night.
你收到求救信号一事非常有趣
I think the fact that you picked up a transmission is very impress...
我们收到从小林丸号舰船发送的遇难信号
We're receiving a distress signal from the USS Kobayashi Maru.
星舰已失去动力  处于困境
The ship has lost power and is stranded.
星际舰队司令部命令我们前往救援
Starfleet command has ordered us to rescue them.
"星际舰队司令部命令我们前往救援"..."舰长"
Starfleet command has ordered us to rescue them... captain.
两艘克林贡飞船进入了中立地带
Two Klingon vessels have entered the neutral zone...
并将武器锁定了我们
And are locking weapons on us.
-没关系  -没关系吗
- That's okay. - That's okay?
对  不用担心
Yeah, don't worry about it.
他说"不用担心"
Did he say don't worry about it?
他压根就没打算认真对待模拟作战吧
Is he not taking the simulation seriously?
又有三艘克林贡飞船撤除隐身  瞄准了我们
Three more Klingon war birds decloaking and targeting our ship.
我想  这大概也不成问题吧
I don't suppose this is a problem either?
他们开火了  舰长
They're firing, captain.
通知医疗部准备迎接受损飞船上的...
Alert medical bay to prepare to receive...
所有伤员
All crew members from the damaged ship.
被克林贡人包围的情况下
And how do you expect us to rescue them...
如何拯救他们呢  舰长
when we're surrounded by Klingons... captain?
去通知医疗部
Alert medical.
我们的舰船被击中  护盾剩余60%
Our ship is being hit. Shields at 60%.
我明白
I understand.
我们要如何  回击吗
Should we, I don't know, fight back?
-不  -当然不能
- No. - Of course not.
这是怎么回事  搞什么鬼
What is this? What's going on?
光子炮  准备对克林贡飞船开火
Hm. Arm photons. Prepare to fire on the Klingon war birds.
-是  长官  -詹姆斯  他们的护盾还在
- Yes, sir. - Jim, their shields are still up.
是吗
Are they?
-不  没有了  -对所有敌舰开火
- No, they're not. - Fire on all enemy ships.
每艘一发光子炮就够了  不必浪费弹药
One photon each should do let's not waste ammunition.
锁定目标  瞄准所有飞船
Target locked an acquired on all war birds.
开火
Firing.
所有舰船都已摧毁  舰长
All ships destroyed, captain.
开始拯救被困人员
Begin rescue of the stranded crew.
那么  我们设法摧毁了所有敌舰
So, we've managed to eliminate all enemy ships,
船上无人受伤
No one on board was injured,
对小林丸号船员的成功救援正在进行之中
And the successful rescue of the Kobayashi Maru crew is under way.
那小鬼怎么能通过你的测试
How the hell did that kid beat your test?
我不知道
I do not know.
召开这次会议  是为了解决一件麻烦事
This session has been called to resolve a troubling matter.
詹姆斯·T·柯克  走上前来
James T. Kirk, step forward.
柯克学员  有证据被呈交委员会
Cadet Kirk, evidence has been submitted to this council,
指出你违反了星际舰队章程17.43规章
Suggesting that you violated the ethical code of conduct
所制定的行动守则
Pursuing to regulation 17.43 of the Starfleet code.
在我们开始之前  你有想说的话吗  先生
Is there anything you care to say before we begin, sir?
有  我想我有权面对我的控告人
Yes. I believe I have the right to face my accuser directly?
请站上前来
Step forward please.
斯波克指挥官  我们最杰出的毕业生之一
This is commander Spock. He is one of our most distinguished graduates.
在过去的四年里  他负责编程小林丸号测试
He's programmed the Kobayashi Maru exam for the last 4 years.
指挥官
Commander.
柯克学员  你设法在程序代码中...
Cadet Kirk, you somehow managed to install and activate a subroutine...
安插了一个子程序  改变了测试的条件
In the programming code, thereby changing the conditions of the test.
-你想说的是  -用校园行话来说  你作弊了
- Your point being? - In academic vernacular. You cheated.
让我问个谁都知道答案的问题吧
Let me ask you something I think we all know the answer to.
测试本身就是作弊吧  你根本没打算让人赢
The test itself is a cheat, isn't it? You programmed it to be unwinnable.
你的论点排除了毫无赢面出现的可能性
Your argument precludes the ability of a no-win scenario?
我不相信毫无赢面的情况
I don't believe in no-win scenarios.
那么  你不仅仅违反了规定
Then not only did you violate the rules,
而且根本就没弄懂关键点何在
you also failed to understand the principle lesson.
那就给我点启发吧
Please, enlighten me.
你应该比别人更清楚  柯克学员
You of all people should know, cadet Kirk,
舰长无法逃脱一死
A captain cannot cheat death.
-就我一个人吗  -你父亲
- I of all people? - Your father,
乔治·柯克中尉接过舰长一职之后
Lt. George Kirk assumed command of his vessel...
随即阵亡 不是吗
Before being killed in action, did he not?
我想你大概很不高兴我通过了你的测试吧
I don't think you like the fact that I beat your test.
此外  你未能明白这一测试的目的
Further more you have failed to define the purpose of the test.
-再给我点启发吧  -其目的是为了体验恐惧
- Enlighten me again. - The purpose to experience fear.
在死亡已无可避免时的恐惧
Fear in the face of certain death.
在接受恐惧的同时  控制住自己  管理好船员
To accept that fear and maintain control of oneself and one's crew.
这是星际舰队每一位舰长都应具备的素质
This is a quality expected in every Starfleet captain.
打扰一下  长官
Excuse me, sir.
我们收到瓦肯星发来的求救信号
We've received a distress call from Vulcan.
我们的主要战舰均集结在劳伦星系
With our primary fleet engaged in the Laurentian system,
我在此命令所有学员马上到一号机库报道
I hereby order all cadets to report to hangar 1 immediately.
解散
Dismissed.
-那个尖耳杂种是谁  -我不认识
- Who was that pointy-eared bastard? - I do not know.
不过我喜欢他
But I like him.
巴瑞瑟  联邦星舰法拉古特号
Bracer, USS Farragut.
麦考伊  联邦星舰进取号
McCoy, USS Enterprise.
麦克格拉斯  联邦星舰沃尔科特号
McGrath, USS Walcott.
斯巴德  联邦星舰胡德号
Spader, USS Hood.
欢迎来到星际舰队  祝各位好运
Welcome to Starfleet. Godspeed.
他没叫到我的名字
He didn't call my name.
指挥官  长官  你没叫我的名字  柯克  詹姆斯·T
Commander, sir, you didn't call my name, Kirk, James T.
柯克  你被停学了  意味着在校委会裁决之前
Kirk, you're on academic suspension, that means you're grounded
你必须留在地上
Until the academy board rules.
詹姆斯  校委会的裁决会偏向你的
Jim, the board will rule in your favor.
很有可能
Most likely.
听着  詹姆斯  我得走了
Look Jim, I've gotta go.
好的  你去吧  小心点
Yeah. Yeah, go. Be safe.
-借过  -嗯  嗯  好的
- Excuse me. - Yeah. Yeah. Sorry.
该死
Damn it.
跟我来
Come with me.
乌胡拉  联邦星舰法拉古特号
Uhura, USS Farragut.
普特拉夫斯基  联邦星舰心宿二星号
Petrovsky, USS Antares.
马上各就各位  祝你们好运
Go to your stations and good luck.
-老骨头  我们去哪啊  -你马上就知道了
- Bones, where are we going? - You'll see.
-指挥官  能问一句么  -什么事  中尉
- Commander, a word? - Yes, lieutenant?
-我难道不是您最好的学生之一吗  -你当然是
- Was I not one of your top students? - Indeed you were.
我难道不是曾经多次表露出...
And did I not on multiple occasions demonstrate...
我卓越的听觉能力  并且  恕我引用
an exceptional oral sensitivity, and I quote...
"在子空间数据传输测验中
"An unparalleled ability to identify sonic anomalies...
可分辨出音波异常的卓绝能力"
In subspace transmission tests"?
一直都是  没错
Consistently, yes.
您十分明白  我最大的希望...
And while you were well aware that I'm qualified...
就是能在进取号星舰上服役
And desire to serve on the USS Enterprise,
可您竟然分配我到法拉古特号上
I'm assigned to the Farragut?
这是为了避免表现出偏爱
It was an attempt to avoid the appearance of favoritism.
不  我要去进取号
No. I'm assigned to the Enterprise.
-好吧  你是去进取号  -谢谢
- Yes, I believe you are. - Thank you.
-你在做什么  -帮你的忙
- What are you doing? - I'm doing you a favor.
我不能把你留在那里可怜兮兮的  坐下
I couldn抰 just leave you there looking all pathetic. Take a seat.
坐下 我要给你打一针抗泥蚤...
Let me give you a vaccine against viral infection...
病毒感染的疫苗
From the Ovaran mud flies.
-干嘛  -为了让你出现症状
- What for? - To give you the symptoms.
你在说什么
What're you talking about?
你的左眼很快会失去视力
You're gonna start to lose vision in your left eye.
对  已经开始了
Yeah, I already have.
然后你会出现严重的头疼  大量流汗
Oh, and you're gonna get a really bad headache and flop sweat.
-你管这叫帮忙  - 对啊  你欠我一次
- You call this a favor? - Yeah, you owe me one.
柯克  詹姆斯·T  他没被分派到进取号上
Kirk, James T. He is not cleared for duty aboard the Enterprise.
医务条例规定  治疗与运送一名病人...
Medical code states the treatment and transport of a patient is...
必须听从其主治医生的意见
To be determined at the discretion of his attending physician.
也就是我  所以我要带柯克先生上船
Which is me. So I'm taking Mr. Kirk aboard.
或者  你宁愿去向派克舰长解释
Or you would you like to explain to captain Pike...
为何进取号曲速冲向危机时
Why Enterprise warped into a crisis...
舰上竟少了一名它的主要医官
Without one of its senior medical officers?
-上船吧  -上船  走吧
- As you were. - As you were. Come on.
我可能会吐你身上
I might throw up on you.
詹姆斯  你真该看看这个
Jim, you've gotta look at this.
-詹姆斯  看  -什么
- Jim, look. - What?
我们得替你换件衣服
We need to get you changed.
我觉得不太对劲  好像尿裤子了
I don't feel right. I feel like I'm leaking.
见鬼  尖耳杂种在那
Damn, it's that pointy-eared bastard.
-斯波克先生  -舰长
- Mr. Spock. - Captain.
-轮机部报告  已做好起飞准备  -谢谢
- Engineering reports ready for launch. - Thank you.
女士们先生们  我们最新旗舰的处女航
Ladies and gentlemen, the maiden voyage of our newest flagship
值得比我们今天提供的更加盛大的仪式
Deserves more pompon circumstance that we can afford today.
她的洗礼仪式将是对我们顺利返航的奖励
The christening will just have to be our reward for a safe return.
继续
Carry on.
各舰层  我是派克舰长  准备立即出发
All decks, this is Captain Pike. Prepare for immediate departure.
舵手  推进器
Helm, thrusters.
系具已收回  舰长  港口控制室报告准备完毕
...retracted, captain, dock control reports ready.
推进器点火  离开太空港
Thrusters fired. Separating from space dock.
已离开太空港  舰长  所有舰船准备曲速前进
The fleet's cleared space dock, captain. All ships ready for warp.
-设定到瓦肯星的航线  -是  舰长
- Set course for Vulcan. - Aye-aye, captain.
航线已设定
Course laid in.
最大曲速  冲吧
Maximum warp. Punch it.
-中尉 麦肯纳舵手在哪  -他患上肺虫了  长官
- Lieutenant, where's helmsmen McKenna? - He has lung worms sir.
没法到位
He couldn't report to his post.
-我是苏鲁田光  -你是个飞行员吧
- I'm Hikaru Sulu. - And you are a pilot, right?
毋庸置疑  长官  我...不太确定出了什么问题
Very much so, sir. I'm... I'm not sure what's wrong here.
制动系统还开着么
Is the parking brake on?
关了
No.
我会查出来的  只是...
I figured it out, I'm just...
你松开外层惯性抑制器了么
Have you disengaged the external inertial dampener?
-准备曲速前进 长官  -我们走吧
- Ready for warp, sir. - Let's punch it.
-我们在哪  -医疗部
- Where are we? - Medical bay.
-这可不值得  -苦其体肤对灵魂有好处
- This isn't worth it. - A little suffering's good for the soul.
你好啊
Hi, how are you?
我嘴巴痒痒 这正常吗
My mouth is itchy. Is that normal?
那些症状不会持续很久的
Well, those symptoms won't last long.
我再给你一针中效镇静剂
I'm going to give you a mild sedative.
我真希望不认识你
Oh, I wish I didn't know you.
别幼稚了
Don't be such an infant.
这到底要多久...
How long is it supposed to...
难以置信
Unbelievable.
引擎已至最大曲速  舰长
Engines at maximum warp captain.
俄罗斯神童  你叫什么  柴可  切泼夫
Russian whiz kid, what's your name? Cheikov? Chirpov?
-切科夫少尉  帕维尔·安德烈  长官  -好
- Ensign Chekov, Pavel Andrejevic, sir. - Fine.
切科夫  帕维尔·安德烈  开始全舰任务广播
Chekov, Pavel Andrejevic, begin ship wide mission broadcast.
是  长官  乐意之至
Yes, sir. Happy to.
少尉级授权码  9-5-Wictor-Wictor-2
Ensign authorization code 95 Wictor Wictor 2.
授权码无效
Authorization not recognized.
少尉级授权码  9-5-Victor-Victor-2
Ensign authorization code 95 Victor Victor 2.
成功进入
Access granted.
请各位注意
May I have your attention please.
22:00  遥感勘测仪在中立地带发现异常现象
At 22:00, telemetry detected an anomaly in the neutral zone.
看着像是在宇宙间发生的雷暴
What appeared to be a lightning storm in space.
不久后  舰队收到瓦肯议会发来的求救信号
Soon after, Starfleet received a distress signal from the Vulcan high command
称他们的星球目前地壳活动剧烈
That their planet was experiencing seismic activity.
我们的使命  就是评估瓦肯星的情况
Our mission is to assess the condition of Vulcan
在必要之时帮助其撤离
And assist in evacuations if necessary.
三分钟内  我们将到达瓦肯星  谢谢您的收听
We should be arriving at Vulcan within 3 minutes. Thank you for your time.
雷暴
Lightning storm.
詹姆斯  你醒了  感觉如何
Aah Jim, you're awake. How do you feel?
-老天  -怎么了
- Good God, man! - What? Aah!
-这他妈怎么回事  -疫苗过敏  该死
- What the hell's this? - A reaction to the vaccine. Damn it.
夏蓓尔护士  我需要50毫升可的松
Nurse Chapel, I need 50cc of cortisone.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
请...像是在宇宙间发生的雷暴
May I... Appeared to be a lightning storm in space.
我们得把船停下
We've gotta stop the ship.
詹姆斯  我不是开玩笑  你得把心率降下来
Jim. I'm not kidding. You need to keep your heart rate down.
电脑  标示乘务员乌胡拉所在地
Computer, locate crew member Uhura.
自从毕业后我还没见过这么糟糕的反应
I haven't seen a reaction this severe since medical school.
-我们正驶向陷阱  -该死  詹姆斯  给我站好
- We're flying into a trap! - Damn it, Jim! Stand still.
住手
Stop it!
-乌胡拉  乌胡拉...  -柯克  你在这做什么
- Uhura, Uhura... - Kirk. What're you doing here?
从克林贡囚星发来的信号  具体说什么
Transmission from the Klingon prison planet, what exactly did it say?
见鬼  你的手怎么了
Oh my God, what's wrong with your hands?
是谁攻击了克林贡人
Who is responsible for the Klingon attack?
-那舰船...  -那舰船怎么了
- And was the ship Romu...? - Was the ship what?
-我的嘴巴怎么了  -舌头麻痹
- What's happening to my mouth? - You got numb tongue?
-舌头麻痹  -我能解决
- Numb tongue?! - I can fix that.
-那舰船怎么了  -罗慕伦人
- Was the ship what? - Romulan.
-什么  -罗慕伦人
- What? - Romulan.
-罗慕伦人  -没错
- Romulan? - Yeah.
-对  -对
- Yes. - Yeah!
尼禄舰长  七艘联邦星舰飞过来了
Prod Nero seven Federation ships are on their way.
-詹姆斯  -发生什么了
- Jim! - What's going on?
-詹姆斯  回来  -舰长
- Jim, come back. - Captain!
派克舰长  我们必须停船
Captain Pike, sir, we have to stop the ship.
柯克  你是怎么登上进取号的
Kirk, how the hell did you get on board the Enterprise?
舰长  这家伙正在被疫苗的...
Captain, this man is under the influence of a...
-强烈过敏反应所影响  -老骨头  拜...
- Severe reaction to a vaccine. - Bones, plea...
他现在完全是胡言乱语...
He's completely delusional...
瓦肯星正在经历的并非自然灾害
Vulcan is not a experiencing a natural disaster,
那是被罗慕伦人攻击了
It's being attacked by Romulans.
罗慕伦人  柯克  你今天得到的关注够多了...
Romulans? Cadet Kirk, I think you've had enough attention for one day...
麦考伊  带他回医疗部去  我们一会儿再谈
McCoy, take him back to medical. We'll have words later.
-是 舰长  -长官  与此相同的异常现象...
- Aye captain. - Sir, that same anomaly...
柯克先生无权登上此舰  舰长...
Mr. Kirk is not cleared to be aboard this vessel, captain...
我明白  你的辩论很了不起...
Look, I get it, you're a great...
我很乐意再来一次...
I'd love to do it again with you soon...
-我可以送走这学员...  -你试试看
- I can remove the cadet... - Try it!
这名学员正试图拯救整个舰桥
This cadet is trying to save the bridge!
就要求肩负使命的星舰停止曲速飞行吗
By recommending a full stop mid-warp doing a rescue mission?
这不是救援任务  听我说  这是攻击
It's not a rescue mission. Listen to me. It's an attack.
基于何种理由
Based on what facts?
与此相同的异常现象  在宇宙空间中的雷暴
That same anomaly, a lightning storm in space
我们今天见到的  我出生那天也发生过
That we saw today, also occurred on the day of my birth.
在一艘罗慕伦飞船攻击星舰开尔文号之前
Before a Romulan ship attacked the USS Kelvin.
您知道的  长官  我看过您的论文
You know that, sir. I've read your dissertation.
那艘拥有令人畏惧的先进武器的飞船
That ship, which had formidable and advanced weaponry...
之后没再有人见过或听说过
Was never seen or heard from again.
开尔文号攻击战发生在克林贡星区边缘
The Kelvin attacked a place on the edge of Klingon space.
昨晚23:00  那里发生了一次战斗
And at 23:00 last night there was an attack.
有47艘克林贡飞船被罗慕伦人摧毁  长官
47 Klingon war birds destroyed by Romulans, sir.
据报告罗慕伦人乘坐的是一艘庞大的飞船
And it was reported that the Romulans were in one ship, one massive ship.
你怎么知道这次克林贡人被袭的
And you know of this Klingon attack how?
长官  是我截获并翻译了那条信息
Sir, I intercepted and translated the message myself.
-柯克的报告准确无误  -我们正飞向圈套  长官
- Kirk's report is accurate. - We're warping into a trap, sir.
罗慕伦人正等着我们  我可以保证
The Romulans are waiting for us. I promise you that.
该学员的逻辑分析很有道理
The cadet's logic is sound.
乌胡拉中尉在外星语言学的造诣无人能及
And Lt. Uhura's is unmatched in xenolinguistics.
我们应该明智地接受她的推论
We would be wise to accept her conclusion.
扫描瓦肯星域  彻查有无罗慕伦人的信号
Scan Vulcan space. Check for any transmissions in Romulan.
长官  我不确定能否辨别罗慕伦语和瓦肯语
Sir, I'm not sure I can distinguish the Romulan language from Vulcan.
你呢  你懂罗慕伦语吗  学员
What about you? Do you speak Romulan, cadet?
乌胡拉  三种方言都懂  长官
Uhura. All 3 dialects, sir.
-乌胡拉  去接替中尉  -是  长官
- Uhura, relieve the lieutenant. - Yes, sir.
汉妮蒂  呼叫联邦星舰杜鲁门号
Hannity, hail the USS Truman.
其他舰船已停止曲速飞行且抵达瓦肯星系
All the other ships are out of warp sir and have arrived at Vulcan,
但我们似乎失去了所有联系
but we seem to have lost all contact.
长官  我在没有收到罗慕伦人或其他信号
Sir, I pick up no Romulan transmission or transmission of any kind in the area.
那因为他们被攻击了
It's because they're being attacked.
升起护盾  红色警戒
Shields up. Red alert.
五秒内抵达瓦肯星系
Arrival at Vulcan in 5 seconds.
4...3...2...
4... 3... 2...
-紧急闪避  -遵命  长官
- Emergency evasives. - Running, sir.
-受损情况报告  -偏针仪护盾正常
- Damage report. - Deflector shields are holding.
所有单位  奥尔森轮机长  报告
All stations. Engineering, Olson, report.
整体翻转  右舷转向90度
Full reverse. Come about starboard, 90'
苏鲁  降到它们底下去
Drop us down underneath them, Sulu.
-长官  还有一艘联邦星舰  -照样毁掉
- Sir, there's another Federation ship. - Destroy it too.
发射鱼雷
Fire torpedoes.
舰长  他们正用鱼雷锁定我们
Captain, they're locking torpedoes.
将引擎的所有备用能源都输送给前方护盾
Divert auxiliary power from port nossel to forward shields.
-苏鲁  报告情况  -护盾32%
- Sulu, status report. - Shields at 32%.
对方武器太强大  长官  我们无法再承受一次
Their weapons are powerful, sir. We can't take another hit like that.
-给我接星际舰队指挥部  -舰长
- Get me Starfleet command. - Captain.
罗慕伦飞船将某种高能脉冲装置
The Romulan ship has lowered some kind of high energy pulse device
刺入瓦肯星的大气层
into the Vulcan atmosphere.
它发出的讯号堵塞了我们的通信以及传送
It's signal appears to be blocking our communications and transporter abilities.
所有能量集中到前护盾  所有武器准备开火
All power to forward shields. Prepare to fire all weapons.
武器准备完毕
Weapons ready.
等等
Wait!
-船身  把它放大  -是  长官
- Gohol, magnify! - Yes, sir.
长官  他们致电过来
Captain, we're being hailed.
你们好
Hello.
我是克里斯托弗·派克舰长  您是哪位
I am the captain Christopher Pike. To whom am I speaking?
克里斯托弗  我是尼禄
Hi Christopher. I am Nero.
你已经向星际联邦宣战  如果撤退
You've declared war against the Federation. Withdraw...
我还能同意在中立地点安排一次
And I'll agree to arrange a conference...
与罗慕伦高层之间的会谈
With Romulan leadership at a neutral location.
我并不代表罗慕伦帝国  我们彼此独立
I do not speak for the Empire. We stand apart.
就像你们那位瓦肯船员  不是么  斯波克
As does your Vulcan crew member. Isn't that right, Spock?
恕我冒昧  我相信你我并不相识吧
Pardon me, I do not believe that you and I are acquainted.
不  我们不认识
No, we're not.
还没认识
Not yet.
斯波克  有样东西我要让你看看
Spock, there's something I would like you to see.
派克舰长  你们的传送装置已经无效
Captain Pike, your transporter has been disabled.
你也看到了其他星舰的下场  你已别无选择
As you can see, by the rest of the armada, you have no choice.
你必须亲自驾驶飞船到纳拉达号进行谈判
You will man a shuttle. Come aboard the Narada for negotiations.
就这样
That is all.
-他会杀了你  你知道的  -你将不可能存活
- They'll kill you, you know that. - Your survival is unlikely.
舰长  外交手段毫无用处
Captain, we gain nothing by diplomacy.
到那艘飞船上去是个错误
Going over to that ship is a mistake.
我也同意 你应该重新思考战略
I too agree. You should rethink your strategy.
我明白
I understand that.
我需要接受过高级近身搏击训练的士兵
I need officers who've been trained in advanced hand to hand combat.
我受过训  长官
I have training, sir.
跟我来
Come with me.
柯克  你一起来  反正你也不该呆在这里
Kirk, you too. You're not supposed to be here anyway.
-切科夫  你负责掌舵  -遵命  舰长
- Chekov, you have the con. - Aye, Captain.
准备好红色物质
Prepare the red matter.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
没有传送器  我们没法将自己传离飞船
Without transporters we can't beam off the ship.
我们无法救援瓦肯人  我们完不成任务
We can't assist Vulcan. We can't do our job.
柯克 苏鲁 和奥尔森将从飞船进行太空跳伞
Mr. Kirk, Mr. Sulu and engineer Olson will space-jump from the shuttle.
你们要降落到他们伸进大气的那台机器上
You will land on that machine they've lowered into the atmosphere...
它扰乱了我们的传输  你们进去把它关掉
That's scrambling our gear, you'll get inside, you'll disable it...
然后你们就能被传送回船上
Then you'll beam back to the ship.
斯波克先生  进取号现在由你指挥
Mr. Spock, I'm leaving you in command of the Enterprise.
传送与通信功能一旦恢复
Once we have transport capability and communication back up
你马上联系星际舰队  报告这里的一切情况
You'll contact Starfleet and report what the hell's going on here.
如果其他人都失败了  迅速撤退
And if all else fails, fall back...
与在劳伦星系的舰队会合
And rendezvous with the fleet in the Laurentian system.
柯克  我现在升你为大副
Kirk, I'm promoting you to first officer.
-什么  -舰长
- What? - Captain?
抱歉  但我无法理解人类玩笑话的复杂性
Please, I apologize. The complexities of Human pranks escape me.
斯波克  这不是玩笑
It's not a prank, Spock.
我也不是舰长了  你才是
And I am not the captain, you are.
我们走吧
Let's go.
长官  我们毁掉那钻头后  你怎么办
Sir, after we knock out that drill, what happens to you?
我想  你可能得过来接我了
I guess you have to come and get me.
小心驾驶这船  斯波克  她还是崭新的
Careful with the ship, Spock. She's brand new.
-普利医生  请报告  -我是麦考伊
- Dr. Puri, report. - It's McCoy.
普利医生在第六层甲板  他死了
Doctor Puri was on deck 6. He's dead.
那你刚刚接过了他主任医官的职务
Then you have just inherited his responsibility as chief medical officer.
是  说点我不知道的行不
Yeah, tell me something I don't know.
89号飞船  这里是联邦星舰进取号  你可以...
Shuttle 89, USS Enterprise, you are clear...
-炸药你带着吧  -当然
- You've got the charges, right? - Oh yeah.
都等不及狠踹那些罗慕伦人了
Can't wait to kick some Romulan ass.
-对  -当然
- Yeah. - Oh yeah.
你接受过哪种搏击训练
So what kinda combat training do you have?
击剑
Fencing.
准备跳伞
Pre-jump.
飞船指挥官  你们已离开进取号领空
Shuttle commander, you are clear from USS Enterprise...
先生们  我们就要到达跳伞区域了
Gentlemen, we're approaching the drop zone.
你们只有一次机会降落到平台上
You have one shot to land on that platform.
他们可能有所防备  所以尽量晚点开降落伞
They may have defenses, so pull your chute as late as possible.
3...2...1
3... 2... 1.
记住  进取号没法把你们传送回去
Remember, the Enterprise won't be able to beam you back...
除非你们先关掉那钻头
Until you've turned off that drill.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
外勤小队正在进入大气层  长官
Away team is entering the atmosphere, sir.
两万米高空
20000 m.
正在接近位于5800米处的平台
Approaching the platform at 5800 m.
柯克呼叫进取号  目标距离 5000米
Kirk to Enterprise. Distance to target 5000 m.
离平台还有4600米
4600 m from the platform.
离目标还剩4100米
4100 m to target.
4000米
4000 m.
3000米
3000 m.
2000米  打开降落伞
2000 m. Pull the chute.
-2000米  -快点  打开降落伞  奥尔森
- 2000 m. - Pull your chute, Olson.
不  还不行  还不行
No, not yet. Not yet.
-1500米  -打开降落伞
- 1500 m. - Open the chute!
-奥尔森 打开你的降落伞  -1000米
- Olson, pull your chute! - 1000 m.
奥尔森
Olson!
奥尔森死了 长官
Olson is gone, sir.
柯克着陆了 长官
Kirk has landed, sir.
手给我 快点
Gimme your hand.
炸弹在奥尔森那
Olson had the charges.
我知道
I know.
-我们怎么办  -这样
- What do we do? - This.
干扰信号消失  通信功能已经恢复
The jamming signal's gone. Transport abilities are reestablished.
传送控制中心恢复了  长官
Transporter control is reengaged sir.
启动传感器  我要知道他们对星球做了什么
Check all gravitational sensors. I wanna know what they were doing to the planet.
是  指挥官  舰长  抱歉  舰长
Aye, Commander. Captain. Sorry, captain.
钻头被破坏  长官  不过我们已经钻至地核
The drill's been sabotaged sir but we have reached the planet's core.
发射红色物质
Launch red matter.
柯克呼叫进取号  他们往星球上发射了东西
Kirk to Enterprise. They just launched something at the planet...
直接进入他们刚钻的洞里
Through the hole they just drilled.
-听到了吗  进取号  -听到了  长官
- Do you copy Enterprise? - Yes, sir.
舰长 引力传感器超过读数范围
Captain, gravitational sensors are off the scale.
如果我的计算正确  他们正制造一个奇异点
If my calculations are correct, they're creating a singularity...
足以吞噬整个星球
That will consume the planet.
他们在瓦肯星中心制造了一个黑洞
They're creating a black hole at the center of Vulcan?
是的
Yes.
星球还剩多少时间
How long does the planet have?
几分钟  长官  几分钟而已
Minutes, sir. Minutes.
向瓦肯议会中心发出警报  撤离整个星球
Alert Vulcan command center to signal a planet wide evacuation...
用所有频道 所有频率
All channels, all frequencies.
-斯波克  等等  -保持标准轨道
- Spock, wait. - Maintain standard orbit.
-是  长官  -你去哪
- Yes, sir. - Where are you going?
去撤离瓦肯长老会
To evacuate the Vulcan High Council.
他们的职责是保护我们的历史文化
Their task is to protect our cultural history,
-我的父母也在其中  -你不能把他们传上来吗
- My parents will be among them. - Can't you beam them out?
那不可能  他们呆在卡催克方舟里
That is impossible. They will be in the Katric ark.
我得亲自去接他们
I must get them myself.
-切科夫  你负责掌舵  -是
- Chekov, you have the con. - Aye.
柯克呼叫进取号  把我们传出这里
Kirk to Enterprise. Beam us out of here.
请准备  正在锁定你们的信号
Stand by, locking on your signal.
-收起钻头  我们走吧  -是  长官
- Retract the drill. Let's move out - Yes, sir.
收起钻头
Fold up.
我没法跟踪他们  别动  别动
I can't lock on to them. Don't move. Don't move!
苏鲁
Hey, Sulu!
Sulu!
坚持住
Hold on.
我抓住你了  快打开我的降落伞
I've gotcha. Now pull my chute.
柯克呼叫进取号  我们正在下落  没有降落伞
Kirk to Enterprise! We're falling without a chute!
快传我们上去
Beam us up!
抱歉我追踪不上你们的信号
I'm sorry I can't lock on to your signal.
-传我们上去  -你们移动太快了
- Beam us up! - You're moving too fast.
我能做到  我能做到
I can do that. I can do that!
-你掌舵  -是  长官
- Take the con. - Aye, sir.
黑洞正在扩张
The black hole's expanding.
不马上离开  我们就无法到达最小安全距离
We won't reach minimum safe distance if we don't leave immediately.
让开  让开 我能做到  我能做到  让开  让开
Move. Move... I can do that. I can do that. Move. Move...
-让我人工控制  我能追踪到他们  -传我们上去
- Give me manual control, I can lock on. - Beam us up!
-进取号  你们在干嘛  -坚持住  坚持住  坚持住
- Enterprise, where are you? - Hold on. Hold on! Hold on!
现在  现在  就现在  快啊  现在  现在
Now! Now! Now! Do it now! Now! Now! Now!
坚持住  坚持住  修正重力牵引作用  然后...
Hold on. Hold on. Compensating gravitational pull. Aaand...
搞定
Gotcha.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - No problem.
清空发射台  我要到地面去
Clear the pad. I'm beaming to the surface.
什么地面
The surface of what?
什么  你要下去  疯了吗
What, you're going down there? Are you nuts?
-斯波克  你不能那么做  -启动
- Spock, you can't do that. - Energize.
斯波克
Spock?
星球仅剩几秒钟  我们必须离开
The planet has only seconds left, we must evacuate.
母亲  快走
Mother, now.
斯波克呼叫进取号  传我们上去
Spock to Enterprise. Get us out now.
正在锁定  别动  呆在原地
Locking on to you. Don't move. Stay right where you are.
传送准备  五  四  三  二...
Transport in 5... 4... 3... 2...
-妈妈  -我要失去她了  我要失去她了
- Mother! - I'm losing her! I'm losing her!...
我失去她了  我找不回她了
I've lost her! I've lost her.
启动舰长日志  星际历2258.42
Acting captain's log, star date 2258.42.
派克舰长未能给我们发来只字片语
We have had no word from captain Pike.
因此我确定他已成为
I have therefore classified him a hostage...
名为尼禄之战犯的人质
of the war criminal known as Nero...
尼禄  他毁了我的母星及其六十亿居民
Nero, who has destroyed my home planet and most of its 6 billion inhabitants.
虽然我们文化之精髓  因守护它的长老们
While the essence of our culture has been saved...
登上这艘飞船而得以保存
in the elders who now reside upon this ship...
我估计幸存者不会超过一万人
I estimate no more than 10000 have survived.
我现在成了濒危物种的一员
I am now a member of an endangered species.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
真的很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
你需要什么  告诉我吧
What do you need. Tell me. Tell me.
我要每个人...
I need everyone...
都能继续出色工作
to continue performing admirably.
好的
Okay.
你肯定有很多问题想问我
You must have a lotta questions for me.
我只有一个要问你的
I only have one for you.
我要星际舰队  边境防护屏障的子空间频段
I need the subspace frequencies of Starfleet's border protection grids.
尤其是包围着地球的
Specifically those surrounding Earth.
克里斯托弗  回答我的问题
Christopher, answer my question.
不  你回答一下
No, you answer for the...
为何刚刚对一个和平的星球进行种族灭绝
Genocide you just committed against a peaceful planet.
不  我避免了种族灭绝
No, I prevented genocide.
在我那时候来的那地方  这只是一艘采矿船
In my time, where I come from, this is a simple mining vessel.
我选择了用辛勤劳动
I chose a life of honest labor.
来养活自己和即将分娩的妻子
to provide for myself and the wife who was expecting my child.
我那时离开了星球去工作...
I was off planet doing my job...
而你们星际联邦就眼睁睁地...
While your Federation did nothing.
坐视我的同胞们  随着星球爆炸而粉身碎骨
And allowed my people to burn while their planet broke in half.
还有斯波克  他没来帮助我们  他背叛了我们
And Spock, he didn't help us. He betrayed us.
不  你迷糊了  你的消息是错误的
No, no... you're confused. You're misinformed.
罗慕伦星球并未被毁
Romulus hasn't been destroyed.
它现在好端端的
It's out there right now.
你为某件未曾发生的事情  而谴责星际联邦
You're blaming the Federation for something that hasn't happened...
它发生了  我亲眼看着它发生  我看到了
It has happened! I watched it happen! I saw it happen!
少跟我扯什么它没发生
Don't tell me it didn't happen!
我失去她的那时  我向自己保证  要他们赔偿
And when I lost her. I promised myself retribution.
25年来  我计划着  该如何向星际联邦寻仇
And for 25 years I planned my revenge against the Federation.
忘记了所谓的正常生活是什么样
And forgot what it was like to live a normal life.
但我没有忘记痛苦
I did not forget the pain.
现在每一个幸存的瓦肯人都与我共享痛苦
It's a pain that every surviving Vulcan now shares.
我的目的  克里斯托弗
My purpose, Christopher,
不仅仅是
Is to not simply...
让我所爱的家园免遭破坏
Avoid the destruction of the home that I love...
还要建立一个  独立于联邦之外的罗慕伦
But to create a Romulus that exists free of the Federation.
只有到那时  她才能真正被拯救
You see only then will she be truly saved.
所以  我要摧毁  现存的每一个联邦星球
That is why I will destroy all the remaining Federation planets.
就从你的开始
Starting with yours.
那我们就没什么好说的了
Then we have nothing left to discuss.
你会告诉我  解除地球防御系统的频段的
You will give me the frequencies to disable Earth's defenses.
人马座蠕虫  它们会寄居到你的脑干上...
Centaurian slugs. They latch on to your brain stem...
释放一种毒素  强迫你回答问题
And release a toxin that will force you to answer.
频段  请说吧  先生
Frequencies please, sir.
克里斯托弗·派克  联邦星舰进取号舰长...
Christopher Pike, captain of the USS Enterprise...
如你所愿
As you wish.
你确定尼禄是往地球去了吗
Have you confirmed that Nero is heading for Earth?
他们的行进轨道上  没有其他目的地  舰长
Their trajectory suggests no other destination, captain.
谢谢你  中尉
Thank you, It.
他的下一站或许是地球  但我们得假设...
Earth may be his next stop, but we have to assume...
联邦的每一颗星球都是目标
Every Federation planet's a target.
从椅子上起来
Out of the chair.
如果星际联邦是目标  为何不摧毁我们
Well, if the Federation is the target, why didn't they destroy us?
他们干吗要  何必浪费武器
Why would they? Why waste a weapon?
我们显然不构成威胁
We obviously weren't a threat.
不是  他说  他要我看什么东西
That is not it. He said he wanted me to see something.
我母星的毁灭
The destruction of my home planet.
顺便问问  他们干吗那么做
How the hell did they do that, by the way?
罗慕伦人从哪得到的那种武器
And where did the Romulans get that kind of weaponry?
人工制造出黑洞所需的必备工程水平...
The engineering comprehension necessary to artificially create a black hole...
或许给出了答案
May suggest an answer.
如此的技术水平  从理论上说...
Such technology could theoretically be manipulated...
完全能制造出穿越时空的隧道
to create a tunnel through space-time.
该死  哥们  我是医生  不是物理学家
Damn it man, I am a doctor, not physicist.
你是当真认为  他们来自未来
Are you actually suggesting they're from the future?
如果你排除不可能的  剩下来的无论多荒谬
If you eliminate the impossible, what ever remains, however improbable...
肯定都是事实
Must be the truth.
真有诗意
How poetic.
那一个来自未来的愤怒罗慕伦人
Then what would an angry future Romulan
想从派克舰长身上得到什么呢
Want with captain Pike?
作为舰长  他当然清楚舰队的所有防御资料
As captain he does know details of Starfleet's defenses.
我们要做的就是追上那艘船
What we need to do is catch up to that ship,
废掉它  接管过来  再带回派克
disable it, take it over and get Pike back.
我们的技术  无论哪个方面都无法企及
We are technologically outmatched in every way.
试图拯救是极不合逻辑的
A rescue attempt would be illogical.
尼禄的飞船不用曲速行进  我们才可能赶上
Nero's ship would have to drop out of warp for us to overtake it.
那不然派技术人员试着提高我们的曲速域
Then what about assigning engineering crews to try and boost our warp yield?
剩下的人员都在修理底层甲板上的...
Remaining power and crew are being used to repair radiation leaks...
-放射性泄漏...  -行了  行了
- On the lower decks... - Okay. Alright. Alright.
以及子空间通信装置的损伤  没有它..
The damage communications. Without it...
-肯定能有办法的  -我们无法联络星际舰队
- There's got to be some way. - We cannot contact Starfleet.
我们必须集合星际舰队其他飞船
We must gather with the rest of Starfleet.
才能在下次遭遇时与之相抗衡
To balance the terms of the next engagement,
不会有下一次遭遇了
There won't be a next engagement.
等我们集合  已经太迟了
By the time we gather it'll be too late.
可你说  他来自未来  他知道将会发生的事情
Look, you say he's from the future and knows what's gonna happen...
那符合逻辑的方法  就是让自己无法预测
then the logical thing is to be unpredictable.
你这是假设  尼禄知道事态将如何发展
You're assuming that Nero knows how event's are predicted to unfold.
恰恰相反  尼禄的出现已经完全改变了历史
The contrary. Nero's very presence has altered the flow of history...
从他对开尔文号星舰的攻击开始
Beginning with the attack on the USS Kelvin,
直至今天达到顶峰
Culminating with the events of today,
因而产生了一系列全新的事件...
Thereby creating an entire new chain of incidents...
那是双方都无法预测的
that cannot be anticipated by either party.
一个平行宇宙
An alternate reality.
不错
Precisely.
不管我们的生活什么样
Whatever our lives might have been
如果时间统一体被干扰了
If the time continuum was disrupted
我们的命运也就改变了
Our destinies have changed.
苏鲁  确定前往劳伦星系的航线  曲速三前进
Mr. Sulu, plot a course for the Laurentian system. Warp factor 3.
斯波克  别那样
Spock, don't do that.
回舰队所在地去开会  是对时间的极大浪费
Running back to the rest of the fleet for a con fab is a massive waste of time...
这是派克舰长离舰之前下的命令
These orders were issued by captain Pike when he left.
他也命令我们回去救他
He also ordered us to go back and get him.
斯波克  你现在是舰长  你必须得...
Spock, you are captain now. You have...
我很明白我的职责  柯克先生
I am aware of my responsibilities...
我们每浪费一秒  尼禄更接近他的下个目标
Every second we waste Nero's getting closer to his next target.
不错  所以我才告诉你接受事实
That is correct and why I'm instructing you to accept the fact that I'm...
我不能让我们回去...而不是去追踪尼禄
I will not allow us to go backwards... ... instead of hunting Nero down.
卫兵  押他出去
Security, escort him out.
-不  -詹姆斯
- No. - Jim!
把他扔出船去
Get him off this ship.
电脑  我在哪里
Computer, where am I?
地点  织女三星  M级行星  危险
Location: Delta Vega. Class M planet. Unsafe.
西北方向14公里外有一星际舰队哨站
There is a Starfleet outpost 14km to the northwest.
-请呆在分离舱内...  -开什么玩笑
- Remain in your pod... - Oh, you've gotta be kidding me.
星际历2258.42
Star date 2258.42.
因为...因为...随便吧
...For... for... Whatever.
执行舰长斯波克  将我流放到织女三星上
Acting captain Spock has marooned me on Delta Vega.
我估计是因为  违反了保安条例49.09
What I believe to be a violation of security protocol 49.09
其对应处置  乃是将囚犯放在星...
Governing the treatment of prisoners aboard a starship.
詹姆斯·T·柯克
James T. Kirk.
-什么  -你怎么找到我的
- Excuse me? - How did you find me?
你怎么知道我的名字
How do you know my name?
我曾经是  也永远都是你的朋友
I have been and always shall be your friend.
听着  我不认识你
Look, I don't know you.
我是斯波克
I am Spock.
胡说
Bullshit.
能再见到你真是无比的高兴啊  老朋友
It is remarkably pleasing to see you again old friend.
尤其是在今天发生的一切之后
Especially after the events today.
先生  我很感激您今天给我的帮助
Sir, I appreciate what you did for me today
可如果您是斯波克  就该知道我们不是朋友
but if you were Spock, you'd know we're not friends at all.
你恨我  你以抗命为名将我流放至此
You hate me. You marooned me here for mutiny.
-抗命  -是的
- Mutiny? - Yes.
你不是舰长吗
You are not the captain?
不不  你才是舰长
No, no... You're the captain.
派克被抓去当人质了
Pike was taken hostage.
被尼禄吗
By Nero?
你对他了解多少
What do you know about him?
他是个非常棘手的罗慕伦人
He is a particularly troubled Romulan.
请容许我...
Please. Allow me.
这样简单得多
It will be easier.
-你在做什么  -我们的思想  融为一体
- Whoa, whoa. What are you doing? - Our minds, one and together.
再过129年  一颗恒星将会爆炸  银河可能被毁灭
129 years from now, a star will explode and threaten to destroy the galaxy.
那就是我的来处  詹姆斯
That is where I'm from Jim.
未来
The future.
一颗恒星演化成超新星
A star went supernova.
毁灭了其轨迹上的一切物体
Consuming everything in its path.
我许诺过罗慕伦人  会去拯救他们的星球
I promised the Romulans that I will save their planet.
我们装备了最快的飞船
We outfitted our fastest ship.
利用红色物质  我可以制造出一个黑洞
Using red matter I would create a black hole
让它吸收正在爆发的恒星
which would absorb the exploding star.
我还在路上时  难以置信的事情发生了
I was on root when the unthinkable happened.
超新星摧毁了罗慕伦星
The supernova destroyed Romulus.
我没有时间
I had little time.
只能提取出红物质  将它射入超新星
I had to extract the red matter and shoot it into the supernova.
当我准备返航时  我被截击了
As I began my return trip I was intercepted.
他说自己叫尼禄  罗慕伦帝国的最后遗民
- He called himself Nero, - ... collapse of Romulan Empire.
当我试图逃跑时  我们都被黑洞吸了进去
In my attempt to escape, both of us were pulled into the black hole.
尼禄先飞出来  他是首先到达的
Nero went through first. He was the first to arrive.
尼禄和他的同伴  花了25年的时间等我到来
Nero spent the next 25 years awaiting my arrival.
可  对于尼禄而言的几十年
But what was years for Nero
在我不过数秒之瞬
Was only seconds for me.
我穿过了黑洞
I went through the black hole.
尼禄在等着我
Nero was waiting for me.
他认为是我害他失去了自己的世界
He held me responsible for the loss of his world.
他逮住了我的飞船  却没有杀我
He captured my vessel and spared my life.
只为了一个原因  好让我了解他的痛苦
For one reason. So that I would know his pain.
他将我传送到这里  让我亲眼目睹他的复仇
He beamed me here so that I can observe his vengeance.
如他无力挽救自己的星球一般
As he was helpless to save his planet
我也该无力挽救我的
I would be helpless to save mine.
几十亿条生灵因他而涂炭  詹姆斯
Billions of lives lost because of me, Jim.
因为我失败了
Because I failed.
请原谅  情绪转移是思维融合的结果
Forgive me. Emotional transference is an effect of the mind meld.
-所以  你确实有感情  -当然
- So you do feel. - Yes.
穿越时空  你改变了我们所有人的生活
Going back in time you changed all our lives.
詹姆斯  我们得走了
Jim! We must go.
离这不远有一处星际舰队的哨站
There is a Starfleet outpost not far from here.
等等
Wait.
你来的那地方
Where you came from...
我认识我父亲么
Did I know my father?
是的
Yes.
你经常说  你加入星际舰队是因为他的鼓励
You often spoke of him as being your inspiration for joining Starfleet.
他看到了你成为进取号的舰长  并引以为豪
He proudly lived to see you become captain of the Enterprise.
舰长
Captain?
那艘我们必须尽快送你回去的飞船
A ship we must return you to as soon as possible.
-曲速三  长官  -航向1-5-1  三号位
- Warp 3, sir. - Course 151-3.
-劳伦星系  长官  -谢谢  先生们
- Laurentian system, sir. - Thank you gentlemen.
-你想见我  -是的  医生
- You wanted to see me? - Yes. Doctor.
我知道詹姆斯·柯克是你的一位朋友
I am aware that James Kirk is a friend of yours.
我认识到  如你那般支持我是颇为困难的
I recognize that supporting me as you did must have been difficult.
这算是感谢么
Is that thank you?
我只是指出你的难处而已
I am simply acknowledging your difficulties.
能允许我自由发言么  长官
Permission to speak freely, sir.
-欢迎之至  -真的
- I welcome it. - Do you?
很好  你那瓦肯脑袋疯了吗
Okay then. Are you out of your Vulcan mind?
遣走柯克  你的选择符合逻辑
Are you making a logical choice sending Kirk away?
可能吧  但正确的选择呢
Probably. But the right one?
知道么  我们老家有句俗话
Back home we've got a saying.
"要想在肯塔基赛马会上一展身手"
If you're gonna ride in the Kentucky derby...
"就别把最棒的种马留在厩里"
You don't leave your prize stallion in the stable...
有趣的隐喻  医生  因为种马发挥出潜能之前...
A curious metaphor, Doctor, as a stallion must first be broken...
必须先被驯服
Before it can reach its potential.
天啊  你至少可以表现得  好像抉择艰难
My God man. You could at least act like it was a hard decision.
我正打算去帮忙...
I intend to insist in the effort...
修复与星际舰队之间的通信
To reestablish communication with Starfleet.
不过  如果我呜咽着穿过走廊...
However, if crew moral is better served...
能对士气起到更好的鼓舞作用
By my roaming the halls weeping...
我会很乐意遵从你的医学知识
I would gladly defer to your medical expertise.
失陪
Excuse me.
绿血死小鬼
Green blooded little goblin.
干嘛
What?
你明白这有多令人无法接受吗
You realize how unacceptable this is?
-真有趣  -什么
- Fascinating. - What?
好吧  我相信你们只是完成工作
I am sure you're just doing your job,
可你们就不能来得更快一点点吗
But could you not come a wee bit sooner?
我在这呆了六个月了
Six months I've been here.
就靠舰队的蛋白质棒和许诺的大餐撑下来
Living off Starfleet botty nips and a promise of a good meal.
我很清楚这是怎么回事  懂吗
And I know exactly what's going on here.
惩罚  不是么  进行中的
Ok? Punishment, isn't it? Ongoing.
为了显然只是一起意外的事情
For something that was clearly an accident.
-你是蒙哥马利·斯科特  -你认识他
- You are Montgomery Scott. - You know him?
对  就是我  你说对了
Yeah, it's me. You're in the right place.
除非附近还有个辛苦工作却快饿死的军官
Unless there's another hard working equally starved Starfleet officer around.
-我  -给我闭嘴
- Me. - Getup, shut up.
你根本不吃东西  你吃那么个...比如一个豆子
You aren't doing anything. You can eat, like, a bean and you're done.
就行了  我说的可是食物  真正的食物
I'm talking about food, real food.
不过你们现在来了  谢天谢地  它在哪
But you're here now. So, thank you. Where is it?
你实际上是  那位斯科特先生
You are in fact a Mr. Scott...
你提出了  在曲速飞行中进行传送的假设
Who postulated the theory of transwarp beaming?
我说的就是那个  你以为我为什么会在这里
That's what I'm talking about. How'd ya think I wound up here?
我跟我的导师争论了那么一次
I had a little debate with my instructor on the issue...
关于相对论性物理学
Of relativistic physics...
以及它对子空间航行的相符性
And how it pertains to subspace travel.
他似乎认为  传送某物
He seemed to think that the range of transporting...
比如一个柚子  其最远范围
Something like a grapefruit...
只能在100公里内
Was limited to about a 100 miles.
我告诉他  我不仅能把一个柚子  从一颗星球...
I told him that I could not only beam a grapefruit...
传送到同一星系的另一颗星球上
From one planet to the adjacent planet in the same system...
顺带一提  这容易得很
Which is easy by the way...
我还能传送活着的生物
I could do it with a life form.
所以  我用阿齐将军的猎兔犬做实验
So, I tested it on admiral Archer's prize beagle.
-我知道那条狗  它怎么样了
I know that dog. What happened to it?
等它再次出现时  我会告诉你的
I'll tell you when it reappears.
我也不知道  对此我确实很有罪恶感
I don't know. I do feel guilty about that.
如果我告诉你  你曲速传送的理论是正确的
What if I told you that your transwarp theory was correct?
往正以曲速行驶的飞船上传送是可能的呢
That it is indeed possible to beam onto a ship that is travelling at warp speed?
要是那方程式被人发现过  我会听说的
I think that if that equation had been discovered I'd have heard about it.
你之所以还没听说  斯科特先生
The reason you haven't heard of it, Mr. Scott,
是因为你还没发现它
Is because you haven't discovered it yet.
-你来自未来么  -他是  我不是
- Are you from the future? - He is. I'm not.
太酷了  那时候还有三明治不
Well that's brilliant. Do they still have sandwiches there?
她是有那么一点点危险  护盾发射器...
Well, she's a wee bit dodgy. Shield emitters are...
完全被咔嚓了  其他一些东西也是
Totally bum jacked as well as a few other things.
走吧
In you go.
进取号开始她的处女航了  对吧
So, the Enterprise has had it's maiden voyage, has it?
她可是位娴雅淑女
She is one well endowed lady.
我真希望能亲手碰碰她的引擎舱
I'd like to get my hands on her ample nossels,
如果你能听懂轮机师隐语的话
If you'd pardon the engineering parlance.
除了一点  就算我相信你吧
Except, the thing is, even if I believed you.
你来的那地方  我做过的事情
Where you're from, what I've done...
顺带一提  我还没做过
Which I don't, by the way.
你所说的可是传送到正以快过光速行驶的...
We're still talking about beaming aboard the Enterprise...
进取号上  而且它上面还没有适合的接受台
While she's travelling faster than light without a proper receiving pad.
给我出去  这可不是攀登架
Get off there. It's not a climbing frame.
曲速传送  其实就像是
The notion of transwarp beaming...
企图用较小的一颗子弹去打中另一颗...
Is like trying to hit a bullet with a smaller bullet...
而且是蒙着眼睛骑在马上这么做
whilst wearing a blindfold, riding a horse.
那是什么
What's that?
你提出的能完成曲速传送的方程
Your equation for achieving transwarp beaming.
免了吧
You're out of it...
想象一下  我从没想到...
Imagine that. It never occurred to me...
空间也是会运动的...
To think of space as the thing that was moving...
你跟我们一起来吗
You're coming with us, right?
不  詹姆斯  那不是我的命运
No, Jim. That is not my destiny.
你的命...
Your dest...
他...那个斯波克不会相信我的  只有你能解释...
He. The other Spock is not gonna believe me, only you can explain...
-清楚发生的一切  -无论何种情况下...
- What the hell has happened. - Under no circumstances...
都不能让他得知...
Can he be made aware...
我的存在  你必须向我保证
Of my existence. You must promise me this.
你是说  我不能告诉你...
So you're telling me I can't tell you...
我其实是遵循你的命令  为什么不  怎么了
That I'm following you're own orders, why not? What happens?
詹姆斯  这是你不能违反的规则
Jim, this is one rule you cannot break.
为了阻止尼禄  你必须独自指挥你的飞船
To stop Nero, you alone must take command of your ship.
怎么做  踩过你的尸体吗
How? Over your dead body?
希望不是
Preferably, not.
不过  有星际舰队章程619
However, there is Starfleet regulation 619.
619条规定了  任何指挥官...
619 states that any command officer...
如果因情绪化危及手头任务
Who is emotionally compromised by the mission at hand...
就必须放弃指挥权
Must resign set command.
所以  你是说  我得在情感上伤害你们吗
So, you're saying that I have to emotionally compromise you... guys?
詹姆斯  我刚刚失去了我的母星
Jim, I just lost my planet.
我可以告诉你  我的情感受到极大损伤
I can tell you, I am emotionally compromised.
你只需让我表现出来即可
What you must do is get me to show it.
好了  老弟  是死是活  我们搏它一搏吧
Aye then lady. Live or die. Let's get this over with.
不  走开  你不能跟我来  走开啊
You cannot come with me. Go on.
知道么  回到现在  改变历史  那是作弊
Coming back in time, changing history, that's cheating.
我从一位老朋友那里学到的诡计
A trick I learned from an old friend.
生生不息  繁荣昌盛
Live long and prosper.
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott?
斯科特先生  能听到我说话吗
Mr. Scott, can you hear me?
坚持一下
Hold on a second.
不  不
No. No!
涡轮机排泄阀开启
RELEASE VALVE.
Purifier release valve activated.
你没事吧  你没事吧
You all right? You all right?
我脑袋嗡嗡作响  全身湿漉漉  不过其他还好
My head's buzzing and I'm soaked, but otherwise I'm fine.
斯波克舰长  发现入侵者进入涡轮控制甲板
Captain Spock, detecting unauthorized access to water turbine control board.
调出视频记录
Bring up the video.
保安  封锁轮机甲板  涡轮三区有入侵者
Security, seal the engineering deck. We have intruders in turbine section 3.
将激光枪设至击晕档
Set phasers to stun.
站住
Halt!
跟我来吧...
Come with me...
小甜心
cupcake!
你是谁
Who are you?
-我跟他一起的  -他跟我一起的
- I'm with him. - He's with me.
我们正以曲速航行
We're travelling at warp speed.
你们是怎么传送到飞船上来的
How did you manage to beam aboard this ship?
你不是天才么  自己猜啊
You're the genius, you figure it out.
作为飞船的执行舰长  我命令你回答问题
As acting captain of this vessel I order you to answer the question.
我不想说  执行舰长
Well I'm not telling, acting captain.
怎么
What?
怎么了  这没法让你沮丧  是吧
What now? That doesn't frustrate you, does it?
我不肯合作这点...没法让你生气吗
My lack of cooperation, that doesn't make you angry?
-你是舰队的一员么  -我...是  能给我条毛巾么
- Are you a member of Starfleet? - Um... yes. Can I get a towel?
我命令你向我解释  你们怎么能够被传送至...
Under penalty of court martial I order you to explain to me
正以曲速飞行的飞船  否则就上军事法庭吧
How you were able to beam aboard the ship while moving at warp?
-别回答他  -你必须回答我
- Don't answer him. - You will answer me.
-我还是哪边都不选好了  -你怎么了  斯波克
- I'd rather not take sides. - What is it with you, Spock?
你的星球刚刚被毁
Your planet was just destroyed,
你的母亲被杀了  你甚至不为所动
Your mother murdered, and you're not even upset.
如果你以为  这些经历有可能...
If you are presuming that these experiences in any way...
对我指挥飞船的能力造成妨碍  你就错了
Impede my ability to command this ship you are mistaking.
然而  是你说了  恐惧是指挥官的必需品
And yet you were the one who said fear was necessary for command.
你看到他的船了吗  看到他做了什么不
I mean, did you his ship? Did you see what he did?
-嗯  我当然看到了  -你到底怕  还是不怕呢
- Yes, of course I did. - So are you afraid or aren't you?
我不用你来教导我情感的好处
I will not allow you to lecture me about the merits of emotion.
-那你干嘛不阻止我  -离我远点  柯克先生
- Then why don't you stop me? - Step away from me Mr. Kirk.
完全感觉不到愤怒是什么滋味  心碎呢
What is it like not to feel anger or heartbreak?
再或者  想要肆无忌惮地...
Or the need to stop at nothing...
为那个生下你的女人复仇的欲望
To avenge the death of the woman who gave birth to you.
-离我远点  -你什么都感觉不到
- Back away from me. - You feel nothing!
你连算都懒得去算
It must not even compute for you.
-你从来没爱过她  -不
- You never loved her! - No!
斯波克
Spock.
医生  我不再适合这一职务了
Doctor, I am no longer fit for duty.
因为我已受情绪影响  我在此放弃指挥权
I relinquish my command based on the fact that I have been emotionally compromised.
请在航行日志上记录下时间日期
Please note the time and date in the ship's log.
我爱这艘飞船
I like this ship.
太教人兴奋了
You know it's exciting.
恭喜啊  詹姆斯  现在我们没有舰长了
Well congratulations, Jim. Now we've got no captain...
也没他妈的大副可取代他
And no God damn first officer to replace him.
不  我们有
Yeah we do.
-什么  -派克让他当了大副
- What? - Pike made him first officer.
-你开玩笑吧  -多谢支持
- You've gotta be kidding me. - Thanks for the support.
我希望你知道自己在做什么  舰长
I sure hope you know what you're doing, captain.
我也一样
So do I.
注意  进取号所有船员  我是詹姆斯·柯克
Attention, crew of the Enterprise, this is James Kirk.
斯波克先生放弃指挥权  晋升我为执行舰长
Mr. Spock has resigned commission and advanced me to acting captain.
我明白大家都希望能与舰队会合
I know you're all expecting a regroup with the fleet,
但我要改变航线  追踪往地球而去的敌舰
But I'm ordering a pursuit course of the enemy ship to Earth.
我要所有部门  在10分钟内做好战斗准备
I want all departments at battle stations and ready in 10 minutes.
不是我们死  就是他们亡
Either we're going down or they are.
柯克讲话完毕
Kirk out.
说出你的想法吧  斯波克
Speak your mind Spock.
那样很不明智
That would be unwise.
必要之事永远都不会不明智
What is necessary is never unwise.
我仍像小时候一般好斗
I am as conflicted as I once was as a child.
你永远都是两个世界的孩子
You will always be a child of two worlds.
我很感激这点
I am grateful for this.
也感激有你
And for you.
我对那个夺去母亲生命的人感到愤怒
I feel anger for the one who took mother's life.
我无法控制的愤怒
An anger I cannot control.
我相信她会说
I believe, as she would say...
"不必勉强"
Do not try to.
有一次你问我  为何会娶你母亲
You asked me once why I married your mother.
我娶她是因为爱她
I married her because I loved her.
无论如何我们都得悄悄地登上尼禄的飞船
Whatever the case we need to get aboard Nero's ship undetected.
我们不能就那么挥着枪冲进去  詹姆斯
Just can't just go in there guns blazing, Jim.
我告诉你..
I'm telling you to...
-柯克舰长  柯克舰长  -什么事  切科夫先生
- Captain Kirk. Captain Kirk. - Yes, Chekov. What is it?
基于纳拉达号  从瓦肯星系飞出的航线
Based on the Nerada's course from Vulcan...
我预计尼禄会从土星飞过
I have projected that Nero will travel pass Saturn.
就像你说的  不能让尼禄看到  不然会被摧毁
Like you said we need to stay invisible to Nero or he'll destroy us.
如果斯科特先生  能让我们以曲速四前进
If Mr. Scott can get us to warp factor 4...
然后在土星卫星  比如泰坦星后面脱离曲速
And if we drop out of warp behind one of Saturn's moons, say Titan.
土星光环的磁场畸变
The magnetic distortion from the planet's rings...
能保证我们不被尼禄的传感器察觉
Will make us invisible to Nero's sensors.
在那里  只要钻头还未启动
From there, as long as the drill is not activated...
我们可以被传送上敌舰
We can beam aboard the enemy ship.
不错  这个可行
Aye, that might work.
-等一下  小子  你几岁了  -17岁  长官
- Wait a minute kid, how old are you? - 17, sir.
好极了  他才17岁
Oh good, he's 17.
医生
Doctor.
切科夫先生是正确的  我可以证明他的理论
Mr. Chekov is correct. I can confirm his telemetry.
如果苏鲁先生  能够将我们带到特定位置
If Mr. Sulu is able to maneuver us into position
我可以传送到尼禄的船上  偷回黑洞装置
I can beam aboard Nero's ship, steal back the black hole device
可能的话  再带回派克舰长
And if possible bring back captain Pike.
我不会允许你那么做的  斯波克先生
I won't allow you to do that Mr. Spock.
罗慕伦人与瓦肯人拥有共同的祖先
Romulans and Vulcans share a common ancestry.
我们文化的相似之处可以令我更加容易地...
Our cultural similarities will make it easier...
侵入飞船电脑
For me to access the ship's computer...
找出装置的所在地
To locate the device.
还有  我母亲是人类
Also my mother was human.
这使得地球成了我仅剩的家园
Which makes Earth the only home I have left.
那么  我跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
我想引用规章制度  可我知道你会不屑一顾
I would cite regulation, but I know you will simply ignore it.
看看  我们已经开始彼此了解了
See? We are getting to know each other.
准备钻头
Prepare the drill.
飞船停止  三  二  一
All stop in 3... 2... 1.
给我五秒钟  四分之一的脉冲推力
Give me 1/4 impulse burst for 5 seconds.
剩下的我用推进器搞定  听我信号
I'll do the rest with thrusters. On my mark.
好的
Aye.
开动
Fire.
传送室  我们已经在泰坦星上方
Transporter room. We are in position above Titan.
真的  做得好  苏鲁先生  真厉害
Really? Fine job Mr. Sulu, well done.
情况如何  斯考提
How are we Scotty?
难以置信  长官  飞船已经就位
Unbelievably sir. The ship is in position.
无论发生何事  苏鲁先生
Whatever happens Mr. Sulu,
如果你认为  我们已有战略优势
If you think you have the tactical advantage...
直接开火  不管我们是否还在船上  这是命令
You fire on that ship even if we're still on board. That's an order.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
等我们准备传送回来时  我们会联系进取号
Otherwise we'll contact the Enterprise when we're ready to be beamed back.
祝您好运
Good luck.
-我会回来的  -最好如此
- I will be back. - You better be.
-我会一直监视着你的频率  -谢谢你  妮欧塔
- I'll be monitoring your frequency. - Thank you, Nyota.
-她的名字原来是妮欧塔啊  -我无可奉告
- So her first name's Nyota? - I have no comment on the matter.
好吧  如果那敌舰设计用的是普通常识的话
Oky doky then. If there's any common sense in the design of the enemy's ship
我应该会把你们送到货舱某处  不会被看到
I should be putting you somewhere in the cargo bay, shouldn't be a soul in site.
启动吧
Energize.
舰长  有星际舰队的人上船来了
Captain, we have Starfleet officers aboard the ship.
-其中一个是瓦肯人  -不
- One of them is Vulcan. - No.
阿伊尔
Ayel!
-我掩护你  -你确定
- I'll cover ya. - Are you certain?
没错  我掩护
Yeah, I've gotcha.
你知道它在哪吗  黑洞装置
Do you know where it is? The black hole device?
还有派克舰长
And captain Pike.
快走
Move.
他们已经启动了钻头
They have activated the drill.
通讯与传送都不能用了
Communication and transportation are inoperative.
苏鲁  拜托告诉我你抓到时机了
Sulu, please tell me you have them.
否则我们没法把他们传回来
Otherwise we won't be able to beam them back.
柯克和斯波克现在只能靠自己了
Kirk and Spock are on their own now.
我预见到一个新的难题
I foresee a complication. The design of this ship...
他们飞船设计的先进性  远远超乎我的预期
Is far more advanced than I have anticipated.
声纹与脸部识别分析系统启动
Voice print and face recognition analysis enabled.
欢迎回来  斯波克大使
Welcome back ambassador Spock.
真是奇怪
That's weird.
电脑  你的制造者是谁
Computer, what is your manufacturing origin?
星际历2387  由瓦肯科学院委托制造
Star date 2387. Commissioned by the Vulcan Science Academy.
看来你一直对我隐瞒了某些重要信息
It appears that you have been keeping important information from me.
你能够让这东西飞起来  对吧
You'll be able to fly this thing, right?
有什么东西告诉我  我已经有这能力了
Something tells me I already have.
-祝你好运  -詹姆斯
- Good luck. - Jim.
我们这计划的成功率  就统计学上来说...
The statistical likelihood that our plan will succeed...
-不到4.3%  -会起作用的
- Is less than 4,3%. - It'll work.
万一我回不去  -请告诉乌胡拉中尉...
In the event that I do not return please tell Lt. Uhura...
斯波克  会奏效的
Spock, it'll work.
不可思议
Fascinating.
相关程序启动
Startup sequence initiated.
尼禄  命令你的人关掉钻头  不然我就...
Nero, order your men to disable the drill or I will...
我从地球历史中认识了你的脸
I know your face from Earth's history.
詹姆斯·T·柯克被认为是个伟人
James T. Kirk was considered to be a great man.
他成为了联邦星舰进取号的舰长
He went on to captain the USS Enterprise.
但  那是在另一个世界
But that was another life.
被我夺走了的世界  正如我对你父亲所做的
A life I will deprive you of just like I did your father.
尼禄舰长  瓦肯飞船被盗  钻头已被摧毁
Captain Nero. The Vulcan ship's been taken. The drill has been destroyed.
斯波克  斯波克
Spock! Spock!
-开启一个通信频道  -是  长官
- Open a channel. - Yes, sir.
斯波克  我就知道  一有机会我就该杀了你
Spock, I knew I should have killed you when I had the chance.
我在此没收这艘非法获得的飞船
I hereby confiscate this illegally obtained ship...
并命令你们无条件交出飞船投降
And order you to surrender your vessel. No terms.
除掉那艘船
That ship... take it out.
-长官  如果引发红色物质...  -我要斯波克现在死
- Sir, if you ignite the red matter.. - I want the Spock dead now!
-他进行曲速飞行了  -追上他
- He went to warp. - Go after him.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你们这物种比我预期的脆弱太多
Your species is even weaker than I expected.
你连话都没法说
You can't even speak.
什么
What?
我拿到了你的枪
I got your gun.
他在做什么
What's he doing?
斯波克大使  你正处于碰撞航线上
Ambassador Spock, you are on a collision course.
发射所有武器
Fire everything.
导弹飞来  如果被击中  红色物质将被引发
Incoming missiles. If the ship is hit, the red matter will be ignited.
明白
Understood.
舰长  我发现了另一艘船
Captain, I've picked up another ship.
-你在这做什么  -遵循命令啊
- What are you doing here? - Following orders.
进取号  就是现在
Enterprise now!
时机正好啊  斯考提
Nice timing Scotty.
我还从没同时把三个人  自两个地方
I've never beamed three people from two targets
传到同一个接收台上呢
Onto one pad before.
-詹姆斯  -老骨头  -我扶住他了
- Jim. - Bones. - I've got him.
真是太棒了
That was pretty good.
舰长  敌舰已丧失动力  他们的护盾消失了
Captain, the enemy ship is loosing power. They're shields are down.
-连线他们  -是
- Hail them now. - Aye.
我是联邦星舰进取号舰长  詹姆斯·T·柯克
This is captain James T. Kirk of the USS Enterprise.
你们的飞船正处于危机之中  离奇异点太近
Your ship is compromised. You're too close to the singularity
若没援助无法幸存  我们很乐意伸出援手
To survive without assistance which we are willing to provide.
舰长  你在做什么
Captain, what are you doing?
向他们表示怜悯  或许是与罗慕伦人...
Showing them compassion may be the only way...
达成和平的唯一方式
To make peace with Romulus, Spock.
很合逻辑  斯波克  我想你会喜欢的
It's logical, Spock. Thought you'd like that.
不  其实不然  这次不可能
No, not really. Not this time.
我宁可千遍地忍受罗慕伦帝国消亡的痛楚
I would rather suffer the end of Romulus a thousand times,
我宁愿痛苦地死去  也不愿接受你们的援助
I would rather die in agony than accept assistance from you.
那你就受死吧
You've got it.
准备激光炮  发射我们的所有武器
Arm phasers. Fire everything we've got.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
-苏鲁  让我们回家吧  -是  长官
- Sulu, let's go home. - Yes, sir.
-我们为什么不曲速飞行  -正飞着呢  长官
- Why aren't we at warp? - We are, sir.
柯克呼叫轮机部  让我们离开这里  斯考提
Kirk to engineering. Get us out of here, Scotty.
你他妈说对了  舰长
You bet your ass captain.
舰长  我们被引力井吸住了  它吸住我们了
Captain, we're caught in the gravity well. It's got us.
开启最大曲速  冲出去
Go to maximum warp. Push it!
我会让她给出所有力量的  舰长
I'm giving it all she's got captain.
她所有的还不足够  你还有什么
All she's got isn't good enough. What else you got?
好吧  如果我们发射能量核  然后引爆
Ok, if we eject the core and detonate the blast...
冲击波应该能推我们出去  不过我不能保证
Could be enough to push us away. I can't promise anything though.
动手  动手  动手吧
Do it! Do it! Do it!
-把这地方清空快  -是  长官
- Clear the area. Go! - Yes, sir.
父亲
Father?
我可不是我们的父亲
I am not our father.
剩下的瓦肯人如此之少  我们不能彼此忽视
There are so few Vulcans left we cannot afford to ignore each other.
那你为什么把柯克送上船来
Then why did you send Kirk aboard
你自己就能解释清楚一切了
When you alone could have explained the truth?
因为你们需要彼此
Because you needed each other.
我不能透露你们将共同完成的创举
I could not deprive you of the revelation of all that you can accomplish together.
以及你们尚未察觉的
Of a friendship that will define you both.
将造就你们特质的友谊
In ways you cannot yet realize.
你是怎么让他保住秘密的
How'd you persuade him to keep your secret?
他以为  若是他食言了...
He inferred that universe ending paradoxes would ensue
将出现宇宙终结之像
Should he break his promise.
你撒谎了
You lied?
-我...只是暗示  -这是赌博
- Oh. I implied. - A gamble?
这是信任
An act of faith.
我希望你将来  在星际舰队中能继续这点
One I hope you will repeat in the future in Starfleet.
面临灭绝  唯一符合逻辑的便是...
In the face of extinction it is only logical...
我放弃星际舰队使命  帮助重建我们的民族
I resign my Starfleet commission And help rebuild our race.
可是  你完全可以分身两处
And yet you can be in two places at once.
我主张你继续留在星际舰队
I urge you to remain in Starfleet.
我已找到一颗适合建立瓦肯殖民地的星球
I've already located a suitable planet on which to establish a Vulcan colony.
斯波克  这一次  帮你自己个忙吧...
Spock, in this case do yourself a favor...
把逻辑推一边  跟着感觉走
Put aside logic, do what feels right.
由于我惯用的告别方式  会显得额外自私
Since my customary farewell would appear awfully self serving...
所以我只说祝你好运
I shall simply say good luck.
本会议是为詹姆斯·提比留斯·柯克召开
This assembly calls captain James Tiberius Kirk.
你的机智勇敢和对战友们的无私奉献...
Your inspirational valor and supreme dedication to your comrades...
正符合这一职务的最高传统
Is in keeping with the highest traditions of service.
亦为你  船员们以及星际联邦增添无上荣光
And reflect at most credit to yourself, your crew and the Federation.
我很荣幸能颁发给你这一勋章
It is my honor to award you with this commendation.
星际舰队命令28455号  特此宣布  你直接向...
By Starfleet order 28455, you are hereby directed to report to admiral Pike...
联邦星舰进取号派克将军报告  接替职务
USS Enterprise, for duty as his relief.
我接过您的担子  先生
I relieve you, sir.
我放心了
I am relieved.
-谢谢你  先生  -恭喜  舰长
- Thank you, sir. - Congratulations, captain.
你父亲一定会以你为荣的
Your father would be proud of you.
推进器满速了
Thrusters on full.
正按您的命令  调适推进器与脉冲引擎  长官
Firing thrusters and impulse engines at your command, sir.
武器系统与护盾准备完毕
Weapon systems and shields on standby.
港口控制室报告完毕  舰长
Dock control reports ready, captain.
老骨头
Bones.
扣好安全带哦
Buckle up.
斯考提  情况如何
Scotty, how we doin'?
重锂室已达到最高水平  舰长
Dilithium chambers at maximum captain.
给我下来
Get down!
苏鲁先生  准备发动推进器
Mr. Sulu, prepare to engage thrusters.
请准许我登舰  舰长
Permission to come aboard, captain.
请求批准
Permission granted.
既然您尚未敲定大副人选
As you have yet to select a first officer,
我在此不才自荐
Respectfully I would like to submit my candidacy.
若您需要  我可以提供推荐信
Should you desire I can provide character references.
这是我的荣幸  指挥官
It would be my honor commander.
部署推进器  苏鲁先生
Maneuvering thrusters Mr. Sulu.
-推进器准备完毕  -我们走吧
- Thrusters on standby. - Take us out.
遵命  舰长
Aye aye, captain.
宇宙  最后的边境
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER
这是进取号星舰的航程
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE
她将继续去  探索未知的新世界
HER ONGOING MISSION: TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
找寻新的生命以及新的文明
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE FORMS AND NEW CIVILISATIONS
勇敢地航向前人所未至的领域
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO ONE HAS GONE BEFORE.